I'm fine.
平気ですよ
A little snake bite isn't going to stop General Hak.
蛇に噛まれたくらいでどうにかなる ハク将軍じゃありません
Um, Hak?
あの はく
Yes?
はい
何処かの里に下りて 食べ物とか薬を
Couldn't we head down into some village for food and medicine?
Villages are dangerous.
人里は危険です
例え村人が俺らの顔を知らなくても
城の兵は何処に居るでも知れない
Even if the villagers don't recognize us,
soldiers from the castle could be anywhere.
じゃ 今どこへ向かってるの
Then where are we going?
恐らく今 俺らにとって唯一頼れる場所
Probably the only place we can count on now.
Capital Fuuga, my home.
風牙の都 俺の故郷です
Episode 4:   The Wind Tribe
本字幕由✿花語&花丸字幕組✿共同製作
POW
見張りはお昼寝の時間か この部族は
Does guard duty mean nap time in this tribe?
ハク様？
Lord Hak?!
Hey.
あ 久しぶり 十年ぶり
It's been a while. Ten years?
It's been three.
三年ぶりだ
What are you doing here?
何でいんの
将軍 首になったの
Did the great general get fired?
相変わらず緩いな
You guys are as laid-back as ever.
我らは風の部族
We're the Wind Tribe.
We live only as the wind blows.
風の赴くまま逆らわずに生きるのであります
眠い時は眠る
When we're sleepy, we sleep.
Who put you guys on guard duty?
誰だ こんな奴らに見張りにしたの
Hey, that's Lord Hak!
あれ ハク様じゃないか
The young lord!
若長
Lord Hak!
ハク様
When did you come back?
いつ戻ったの
You've become even more handsome!
嫌だ 益々男前になちゃって
頼むから一人つつ喋ってくれ
Please, one at a time.
まだ城から何も聞いてね様だな
Looks like they haven't heard
anything from the castle yet.
My, who is this girl?
あら 誰この子
ハク様の女
Is she your woman?
What?
違う 城の見習い女官だ
No, she's a court lady in training.
No way! So what's your name?
嘘だ な 名前は
Huh?
出身は もしかして空都
Where are you from? Are you from the Sky capital?
Hey, what's Hiryuu Castle like?
ねね 緋龍城ってどんなとこ
How old are you?
あんた今 年は幾つなの
Um...
あの...
倒れちゃった
She collapsed!
あれ まぁ 弱っちい娘だな
Oh, my, what a weak girl.
すぐに寝所と食事の用意を
Prepare a bed and food immediately.
あの若長が女性に優しくしている
The young lord's being kind to a woman.
聞こえなかったのか
Didn't you hear me?
は はい
Y-Yes, sir.
爺ちゃん...ムンドク長老はどこに居る
Where's the old man, Elder Mun-deok?
長老なら 緋龍城だよ
He's at Hiryuu Castle.
なに
What?
やっぱり知らないんだ
You didn't know?
The five tribes were suddenly summoned to a meeting at the castle.
急に城から五部族召集令が下ったんだよ
A meeting of the five tribe?
五部族召集だと
普通なら 城に居る若長が出席すればいいでしょう
Normally, the young lords of the castle attend.
既に将軍を退いたムンドク長老が呼ばれたから
変だなと思ったんだ
I thought it was strange that they summoned Elder Mun-deok,
when he's retired from being a general.
ハク様やっぱり首ですか
Lord Hak, were you really fired?
一体どう言う事だ
What's the meaning of this?
急な呼び出しがあったかと思えば 国王崩御だと
We're called here suddenly,
and they tell us the king is dead?
ヨナ姫もソンハク将軍も行方不明だの事
Princess Yona and General Hak are missing too.
Elder Mun-deok, don't you have some idea where General Hak might be?
ハク将軍の行方についてムンドク長老は何かご存知なのでは
何が言いたい 火の部族の若僧よ
What are you trying to say, Fire Tribe boy?
城内ではこんな噂が広がっておりますぞ
There's a rumor going around the castle
陛下はハク将軍によって殺害され
ヨナ姫は人質として彼に連れ去られたと
that General Hak killed the king and took Princess Yona hostage.
決めつけるのは良くないな
It isn't good to make assumptions.
行方が分からないのだから
ハク将軍にも何かあったのでは
We don't know where General Hak is.
Perhaps something happened to him as well.
That Thunder Beast's strength surpassed mine when he was just thirteen years old.
あの雷獣は齢十三にして我をも凌ぐ力を持っていたんだぞ
He wouldn't die so easily.
そう簡単に死ぬものか
お静かに
Quiet.
Three days ago, the king was murdered,
陛下は三日前 何者かに弑逆され
ヨナ姫もハク将軍も行方知れずです
and both Princess Yona and General Hak are missing.
では やはり...
Then it's true?
この件は我々に任せて頂きたい
Leave this matter to us.
もし彼らを見つけたら 城に連絡を
If you find them, contact the castle.
許可なく危害を加えたり外部に公表したりなさらぬよう
Do not harm them or inform
anyone else without permission.
But...
しかし...
Publicizing this information would bring chaos to the kingdom.
この件を公にすれば 国内の混乱を招き
部族同士の争いを煽るだけでしょう
The tribes would begin fighting among themselves.
Chishin
Fuuga
Kouka Kingdom
Saika
Sei Country
Shin Country
Suiko
The Empire
m 349 48 l 447 48 447 86 349 86
m 382 199 l 431 199 431 227 382 227
m 431 446 l 482 446 482 475 431 475
m 511 507 l 575 507 575 543 511 543
m 540 178 l 673 178 673 213 540 213
m 723 497 l 792 497 792 538 723 538
m 726 326 l 782 326 782 359 726 359
m 771 122 l 822 122 822 151 771 151
今は一刻も早く 我々五部族が力を合わせ
What the five tribes must do now is work together to strengthen Kouka Kingdom.
高華王国を他国に侵されない強国にしなければ
Otherwise, it will be invaded by another country.
確かに
You're right.
イル陛下は争いを避けるあまり
他国に国土を譲り貢物を差し出したわ
To avoid conflict, King Il gave other countries land and made offerings to them.
今や高華王国の権威は地に落ちている
Our kingdom's political influence is all but gone.
国内で争っている時ではない
Now is no time for civil war.
それには 新王が必要ですな
In that case, we need a new king.
恐れながら ヨナ姫が不在の今
With all due respect, in Princess Yona's absence,
王家の血を引いておられるのは
ここに居るスウォン様しかおりますまい
the only one with royal blood is Lord Su-won.
本来なら皇太子のくらいにあるお方
新王に即位されるのに何の問題も御座いません
He should have been the crown prince in the first place.
There's no problem with crowning him as king.
然り スウォン様が新王となられるならば
このカンスジン 誠心誠意お使え申し上げます
I, Kang Su-jin, sincerely approve of
Lord Su-won becoming the new king.
他の部族長は如何ですか
How do the other tribe leaders feel?
え スウォン様ならば
Yes, I approve of Lord Su-won.
異存ありません
No objections here.
I'm tired.
眠い
眠い眠い
I'm so tired.
難しい話は年寄りには眠いわ
Complex discussions tire the elderly.
わしは帰る
I'm leaving.
Lord Mun-deok, we aren't finished yet!
ムンドク様 話はまだ
わしは将軍ではない
I'm no general.
その話はハクを呼んでからにするんじゃな
You should discuss this matter
after you've summoned Hak.
スウォン様を王に承認なさらないのなら
If you refuse to acknowledge
Lord Su-won as the king,
風の部族は益々謀叛の疑いをかけられますぞ
that will be all the more reason to suspect the Wind Tribe of rebellion.
五部族全ての承認を得られなくては私は王にはなれません
Without approval from all five tribes,
I cannot become king.
王がいなければ 国は立ちゆきませんし
But a kingdom won't last without a king.
スウォン様がヨナ姫と婚礼をあげて
正式に高華の王となられるのでしたら
If you were to marry Princess Yona and formally become king,
わしは大喜びで祝いの品を献上したじゃろう
I would happily present you with a celebratory gift.
ハクは理由もなしに城を去ったりはせぬ
Hak wouldn't leave the castle without reason.
三日後 新王即位式を執り行います
Three days from now,
we will hold the coronation ceremony.
ムンドク長老は必ず来て下さると信じています
I know you will come, Elder Mun-deok.
風牙の都の民のためにも
For the sake of the people of Capital Fuuga.
悲しい事です
It's sad.
スウォン様 あなたの事はハク同様 孫の様に思っていた
Lord Su-won, I used to think of you
as a grandson, like Hak.
ご苦労様でした
Good work.
少しお甘いのでは
Shouldn't you be a little more concerned about this?
ヨナ姫やハク将軍を追わず殺さずとは
If you don't hunt down Princess Yona and General Hak and kill them,
もし二人の口から真実が広まれば...
and they spread the truth-
Hak is no fool.
ハクはバカじゃないです
真実を広め騒ぎを起こせば 逆にヨナ姫の命が危ない
If he spreads the truth and starts an uproar,
Princess Yona will be in danger.
姫を守るため 今はじっと息を潜めている事でしょう
I'm sure he'll stay silent for the present,
to protect the princess.
General Kang, begin preparations to quell a Wind Tribe rebellion.
風の部族の反発に備えて
カン将軍は次の計画に移って下さい
御意
As you wish.
ありがとう
Thank you.
I was happy to hear you say that you considered me a grandson, Master Mun-deok.
孫の様にって言ってくれて嬉しかったです ムンドク師匠
どこ
Where am I?
服 新しい
I have new clothes.
起きたのか
Are you awake?
よし 熱は下がったな
Good. Your fever's gone down.
Eat lots of food, and get well soon.
沢山飯食って早く元気になれよ
いい匂い
It smells nice.
It's good.
旨いぞ
何で泣くんだ 不味かった
Why are you crying? D-Does it taste bad?
暖かくて
It's so warm.
暖かくて泣くのか 変な奴だな
You're crying because it's warm?
You're strange.
父上を思い出して
It made me remember my father.
俺はテヨン ハク兄ちゃんの弟だ
I'm Tae-yeon, Hak's younger brother.
ハクの弟
Hak's younger brother?
お前はハク兄ちゃんの友達か
Are you Hak's friend?
たぶん
Probably...
You're probably friends?!
たぶん友達
That's awful. Even if you can't be lovers...
そんな 愛人とか恋人とかは無理にしても
たぶん友達って視界にも入ってねぇっす
...you might not even be friends?
So he's totally out!
哀れ ハク様超片思い
Poor Lord Hak! And his feelings are so strong-
Who are you calling your friend?
誰が友達だ
え じゃ 従者...
Huh? Then, my attendant-
Your name is Rina.
あんたの名はリナ
城の見習い女官と言うことになってる
You're a court lady in training.
Got it?
いいな？
Okay, that's a good girl.
よし いい子だ
There's something naughty about this, Lord Hak!
だっておやらしいよハク様
We aren't doing anything Tae-yeon shouldn't see!
テヨンが見て不味い事はなんもしてねぇだろが
Rina, what is my brother like at the castle?
リナ 兄ちゃんは城ではどんな人なの
At the castle, Hak is...
城でのハクは
If anything isn't right, it would be her brain.
脳味噌が変ですね
...rude.
無礼者
No, he's insensitive and arrogant. Oh, and not lovable. Also-
あいや 無神経 えっと態度でっかい うん可愛くない 後...
Okay, we get it. That's enough.
よし分かったもういい
Miss Rina, you're the best.
リナさん最高
Nothing lovable about him!
そりゃ可愛くねぇわ
You two look like you're having fun.
楽しそうだな二人共
皆笑顔で賑やか これがハクの育った場所
Everyone's smiling and lively.
Come here.
This is where Hak grew up.
ねね 城ってどんなとこなの
Hey, what's the castle like?
Do they have lots of good food?
ご馳走いっぱいなのか
Yes, but your food tastes better.
うん だけどテヨンのご飯が一番美味しい
お代わりあるから いっぱい食えよ
There's more, so eat lots!
Okay.
Rina, did you sleep well last night?
リナちゃん 昨日はよく眠れた
Hey, Rina!
ちょっと リナちゃん
Oh, yes.
あ はい
Right, I'm Rina.
私の事か
You're such an absent-minded girl.
ぼっとした子だね
I heard you were thrown out of the castle.
あんた城追い出されたんだって
They said you couldn't cook, sew, clean, do laundry, play the koto, or even dance.
聞いたよ 料理も裁縫も掃除も洗濯も琴も舞も出来なかったって
Don't worry. I'll teach you everything from scratch.
心配しなくていいよ あたしが一から教えてあげる
First, wash these.
まずこれ 洗っといて
W-Wash them?
あ 洗うって
任せたよ
I'll leave it to you.
Um, I...
あの...
This way, my lady.
こちだ 女官殿
What is it?
なんですか
I can play the koto and dance a little.
琴と舞はちょっとなら出来るわ
Oh, right. That cacophony.
あぁ あの不協和音ね
You're a bit more like yourself.
少し戻ってきたな
Huh?
Nothing.
何でもありません
So you have a younger brother.
ハクに弟が居たのね
He's cute. Nothing like you.
可愛くて ハクに似てない
Sorry about that.
悪かったな
テヨンは俺と同じ 爺ちゃんが拾ってきた子なんですよ
Grandpa took Tae-yeon in, just like me.
Unlike me, he's frail.
俺と違って体が弱い
That's why everyone's especially nice to him.
だから特別皆が大事にしてるんです
He got a bit too excited yesterday.
昨日はちょっと燥ぎ過ぎてたな
We're here. We wash clothes in that river.
着きましたよ そこの川で洗濯するんです
Its water is the Wind Tribe's life,
so be careful with-
風の部族にとって命の水だから 大事に...
Hak, I can't.
ハク 出来ない
You haven't done anything yet.
あのな まだ何もしとらんだろが
But...
だって...
The river has dried up.
川が枯れてる
川の水がない
There's no water in the river.
Calm down!
落ち着け
We're sending Hean-dea to check
on conditions upriver.
今ヘンデを上流の調査に向かわせている
Young lord, this isn't the time
to be so unconcerned!
若長 そんな悠長な事言ってる場合かよ
騒いだ所で事態は変わらねぇだろ
Making a fuss won't fix anything.
For now, we can buy water from the merchants.
水は当分商団から買えばいい
They should have enough reserves to see us through the current situation.
当座を凌ぐくらいの蓄えはあるはずだ
ムンドク長老が帰ってきた
Elder Mun-deok has returned!
Grandpa!
Princess.
姫様
You're all right.
ご無事だったか
よかった
Thank goodness.
信じたくなかったが
I didn't want to believe it,
but when I heard the king was dead, and you'd left the castle with Hak...
陛下が亡くなられてあんたとハクが城を去ったと聞き
I'm sorry I couldn't protect you then.
その時お守り出来ず 口惜しい
Mun-deok...
ムンドク...
I can't breathe.
苦しい
Have you lost weight?
少しお痩せになられましたが
うん 暖かいもの 美味しいもの 沢山貰ったの
No. I've been given many warm
and delicious things to eat.
The Wind Tribe is like you, Mun-deok.
風の部族はムンドクみたい
暖かくてほっとする
It's warm and reassuring here.
Brother!
兄ちゃん
爺ちゃん
Grandpa!
ヘンデが戻ったぞ
Hean-dea's back.
Hean-dea, your injuries...
ヘンデ その傷は
What happened?
何があった
I messed up.
いやいや ちょっと失敗しちゃって
I went upriver, and would you believe it,
上流に行ったらびっくり
火の部族の奴らが川を塞き止めてたからさ
some guys from the Fire Tribe were damming the flow.
思わず武装した奴らに喧嘩売っちゃったのね
I thoughtlessly picked a fight with them,
but they were armed.
そしたらぼこぼこでぽいよ
They beat the snot out of me.
The Fire Tribe...
火の部族
What are they trying to do?
奴ら何してくれちゃってんだ
俺らと戦争でもやるのか
Do they want a war with us?
Lord Hak, let me go!
ハク様 俺に行かせてください
I'll beat them up.
ぼこぼこにしてやる
待って 火の部族に手を出してはならん
Wait. You mustn't attack the Fire Tribe.
Why? They stopped up the river
and tried to kill Hean-dea!
何で 奴ら川を止めてヘンデを殺したいんっすよ
このままだと風牙の都が...
At this rate, Capital Fuuga will be...
落ち着け 川の事なら心配いらん
Calm down. Don't worry about the river.
In any case, hurry up and treat Hean-dea.
とにかくヘンデの治療を急げ
はい
Yes, sir.
ほら 行くぞ
Let's go.
Wait! I'm still alive!
Grandpa.
これは火の部族の警告じゃ
This is a warning from the Fire Tribe.
A warning?
警告
They want to crown Lord Su-won king.
奴らはスウォン様を王に即位させたがっている
わしが王に承認せんから圧力をかけてきたんじゃろう
They're pressuring us because I didn't approve.
父上を殺したスウォンがこの国の王になる
Su-won, who killed my father,
will be king of this country?
姫様
Princess.
It's all right. I will never approve.
大丈夫じゃ 承認はせぬ
If I acknowledge Lord Su-won as king,
スウォン様を王に認めてしまったら
ハクに国王殺害の疑いがある事も認めてしまう事になる
it would also mean acknowledging that Hak may have killed the king.
だろうな 俺に罪を着せるのが一番手っ取り早い
You're right. Blaming me would be the fastest way.
ハク
Hak...
Don't worry.
心配はいらん
The Fire Tribe won't do anything worse than this.
火の部族とて これ以上の無茶はせんじゃろう
How is the Wind Tribe reacting?
風の部族の様子はどうだ
今の所 動きはないですね
They haven't made a move yet.
この分だと数日内に音をあげ...
At this rate, we should see some
commotion in a few days-
つめが甘いな 川を止めてそれで終わりか
It isn't enough. Are we just damming the river?
はい スジンからはその様に仰せつかってますが
Yes. That's what General Su-jin ordered us to do.
Merchants visit the Wind Tribe regularly.
風の部族には定期的に商団が来るらしいな
If they purchase water from the merchants, this will prove pointless.
商団から水を買われては意味がない
Crush them before they reach Capital Fuuga.
風牙の都に着く前に潰せ
But we shouldn't act without
General Su-jin's approval.
しかし スジン将軍のお許しを得ずに勝手な事は...
山賊か何かの仕業に見せかければいいだろう
Make it look like the work of bandits!
Why are you so upset, Lord Tae-jun?
何をいらいらしてるんですか テジュン様
If I had acquired Princess Yona,
the throne would've been mine.
ヨナ姫を手に入れていれば
玉座は私のものだったのに
If only Hak hadn't interfered!
あの時ハクが邪魔しなければ
Are you being serious?
マジで言ってんの
Su-won will ascend the throne.
スウォンが即位する
The other tribes approved.
そして風以外の部族はそれを認めた
What will happen to the Wind Tribe?
風の部族はどうなるの
Rina.
リナ
どうした お腹すいた
What's wrong? Are you hungry?
ご飯だぞ
It's time for dinner.
There's not enough water,
but you're giving me so much.
水が不足してるのに 私ばかり
大丈夫 リナを太らせてこいってハク兄ちゃんが...
It's okay. Hak told me to fatten you up.
それにお客様にはたんまりおもてなしして銭貰うのが
Besides, Hak said it's the Wind Tribe's way to pamper guests,
so they'll give us money.
風の流儀だって...
Tae-yeon?
テヨン
Tae-yeon?!
What's wrong?
どうした
He suddenly collapsed!
急に倒れて
He's having a fit.
発作じゃ
Tae-yeon's lungs have always been weak.
テヨンは昔から肺が悪くて 時折呼吸麻痺を起すんじゃ
Sometimes, he gets respiratory paralysis.
Once he takes his medicine, he'll be fine.
なに 薬を飲めばすぐ...
それが今日来るはずの商団がまだ来ねぇんだ
But the merchants who were supposed to arrive today haven't come yet.
I'll go check it out.
俺 見てくる
It's an emergency!
大変だ
The merchants were attacked on their way here!
商団がここに来る途中 何者かに襲われた
No!
そんな
They're all seriously injured.
皆大けがを負ったって
では水を手に入れる手段は絶たるだろか
Then we've lost our means of acquiring water?
The medicine...
薬は...
What about Tae-yeon's medicine?
テヨンの薬は
Damn it.
クソ
火の部族の仕業に決まってる
This must be the Fire Tribe's work!
I can't let this slide!
もう許さん
Young lord, why aren't you saying anything?
若長 何黙ってんだよ
This isn't like you, Elder.
らしくないですよ 長老
The royal family stands behind the Fire Tribe.
火の部族の後ろには空 王族が居る
If we antagonize them,
the Wind Tribe won't escape unscathed.
敵に回せば 風の部族はただで済まされねぇ
いや もう誰かが死ぬ所を見たくない
No. I don't want to see anyone else die!
Hean-dea, your injuries...
ヘンデ お前けが...
Okay, okay! Calm down, you hot-blooded idiots!
はいはい 血の気の多いバカ共落ち着け
You attacked them first.
お前が先に特攻したんじゃねか
The most important thing right now is Tae-yeon's medicine, isn't it?
とりあえず今一番大事なのはテヨンの薬だろ
I'll go to the doctor in the eastern forest and get some medicine.
俺東森の医術師のとこ行って薬貰ってくるわ
You'll go all the way there, despite your injuries?
あんな所までそのけがでか
I'm the fastest rider in the Wind Tribe.
俺風の部族一速く馬を駆れるもん
You okay with that, young lord?
ね いいでしょう 若長
Leave it to Hean-dea!
ヘンデにお任せ
薬代 値切れよ
Haggle down the price of the medicine.
では
I'm off.
He's so reckless.
無茶しやがって
てめえら 聞け
Listen, everyone.
I understand your rage,
but the Fire Tribe is strong.
お前らの怒りは分かるが
火の部族は相当な兵力を持っている
I won't let you start a war with them now.
今戦争すんのは許さねぇ
I promise I'll do something about this.
この件は必ず俺が何とかする
It's not like we'll shrivel up just because the river has run dry.
川が止められたからって
すぐに干涸らびる俺らじゃなし
Entrust your lives to me, and wait quietly.
俺に命預けたと思って黙って待ってろ
Those are the orders of Son Hak,
Chief of the Wind Tribe.
風の部族長 ソンハクの命令だ
Did you hear that?
聞いたか
The young lord gave us orders.
若長が命令だ何て
Lord Hak...
The Lord Hak who said becoming
a general would be too much work!
面倒くさがって将軍嫌がってたハク様が...
His condition is improving.
少し持ち直したな
You should get some rest.
You'll collapse again.
いい加減あんたも休め またぶっ倒れるぞ
Hak, is there anything I can do?
ハク あの...私には何かできる事...ない
Well, a court lady should try to be a little sexier.
そうだな 女官殿はもうちょっと色気を身につけるこったな
Wha-
Hak, I'm being serious here.
ハクお前 私が真面目な話を...
It's fine. You can live a carefree life here.
いいんだよ あんたはここでのんびり暮らせば
What's wrong? You can't sleep?
どうした 眠れんのか
What about you?
長老様こそ
Since neither of us can sleep,
why don't we have a drink?
眠れない同士 一杯どうですか
It's rare for you to offer me such good sake.
珍しいな お前がわしにこんな良い酒を
No. This is from your prized sake cellar.
いや これはじじ秘蔵の酒蔵から...
もったいねぇな
What a waste.
So... what do you want?
で...何の用じゃ
I've been thinking.
ちょっと考え事
If it were you alone,
爺ちゃんがたった一人なら
you probably would've charged into the castle with a single spear.
槍一つ掲げて城に乗り込んだんだろなって
You're one to talk.
小僧が人の事言えるのか
You're putting too much stress
on your body, old man.
老体に色々背負い込みすぎだろ じじ
頼みがある
I have a request.
スウォンの新王即位を承認してくれ
I need you to approve of Su-won
becoming the new king.
Tomorrow morning, I'm leaving the Wind Tribe.
俺は明朝 風の部族を去る
You can have the Son name back too.
あんたにソンの名をお返しする
あんたは風の部族を守る事だけ考えてくれ
Think only of protecting the Wind Tribe.
承認すれば火の部族も手出しはしないはずだ
Once you approve, the Fire Tribe should stop bothering you.
You may end up with a bounty on your head.
賞金首にでもされるかもしれんぞ
That sounds cool. Maybe I'll become Kouka's greatest villain.
いいね 高華一の悪党にでもなるか
姫様は置いてゆく気か
Are you leaving the princess behind?
She's finally able to smile a little again.
ようやく少し笑える様になってきた
連れてきてよかったと思ってる
I'm glad I brought her here.
頼みはもう一つ
I have another favor to ask of you.
ヨナ姫を城から隠し
Hide Princess Yona from the castle,
一生ここで風の部族の人間として生かしてやってくれ
and let her live her whole life
as a member of the Wind Tribe!
No.
嫌じゃ
I refuse to take requests from my grandson.
孫のお願いなんじゃ わしは聞かん
わしはお前を手放したりせんぞ
I won't let you go.
Old man...
部族長の命なら 従わん訳にもいかんが
Though I suppose I can't
disobey my chief's orders.
風の部族長ソンハク 最後の命令だ
Those are the final orders of Son Hak,
Chief of the Wind Tribe.
As you wish.
御意
Do you see
wakaru kai
What I'm trying so hard to convey through my work?
muriyari demo sakuhin de tsutaetokitai koto wo
It's always been this way, hasn't it?
mukashi to kawaranai daro
The same obscure lyrics and background
yomizurai kashi mo haikei mo
I've always talked ideals
sasaeru da to ga erasou ni sa
Like supporting others
nando mo nando mo itta kedo
I hope you don't realize too early
kotoba no karusa omoishiru no wa
How irresponsible I was being with my words
hayasuginai you ni
There's a reason why the snow is so cold
yuki ga tsumetai wake nante
Since my hands are warmer than others'
boku no te ga hito yori atsui kara
When I hold your hand
kimi no sono te wo tsunaida toki
I'll be able to bring out the warmth in you
atatakai wo hikidasu tame
Next Time
私は何の為に風牙の都を出だの
Why did I leave Capital Fuuga?
Only to live, protected by Hak?
ただハクに守られて生きる為？
次回 暁のヨナ 第五話
Next time, Akatsuki no Yona, episode 5:
Episode 5:   Howl
咆哮
Howl.